<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Miscs on Diary Of An Observer</title>
    <link>http://pvsukalkar.in/misc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Miscs on Diary Of An Observer</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:30:23 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://pvsukalkar.in/misc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mobile Phone Addiction</title>
      <link>http://pvsukalkar.in/misc/mobile-phone/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:30:23 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pvsukalkar.in/misc/mobile-phone/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Samu is 1 year old now. As parents, we often get advised to keep child away from mobile phone as he would get addicted to it.&#xA;That is indeed true. If Samu sees any kid&amp;rsquo;s video on youtube, he gets hooked to it. When the screen is turned off,&#xA;he screams as if why did you turn off the video.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I usually don&amp;rsquo;t like classifying things as good or bad. There are actions and their consequences.&#xA;Samu likes youtube videos is a fact. I just try to utilize it to his benefit.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sip by Sip</title>
      <link>http://pvsukalkar.in/misc/sip-by-sip/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 01:07:56 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pvsukalkar.in/misc/sip-by-sip/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There was something off about Samu today. We had gone to Vikas&amp;rsquo; home for his daughter&amp;rsquo;s birthday.&#xA;Samu kept crying there every now and then. We also left the function early and were thinking of taking Samu to hospital.&#xA;Probably there was some issue with his stomach. Maybe gas or something, is what we assumed.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While driving back home, Samu&amp;rsquo;s crying continued in car too. This is unusual for Samu. He usually does not cry in car.&#xA;So, we played his favorite &lt;code&gt;Aha Tamatar bade mazedar&lt;/code&gt; song and he kept quiet for some time. But he needed constant feeding.&#xA;Sonal was also getting agitated by this behaviour as it was her period day.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Closing the door on Hope</title>
      <link>http://pvsukalkar.in/misc/hope/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 01:55:11 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pvsukalkar.in/misc/hope/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sonal was doing her yoga in hall and Samu was quite active as it was morning.&#xA;He wanted to do everything but sleep. It is usually his nap time but he wasn&amp;rsquo;t feeling sleepy.&#xA;So, I took him to guest room (which is attached to hall).&#xA;I was hip carrying Samu, strolling and singing &lt;code&gt;Are Kanha, Are Krishna&lt;/code&gt; angaai (lullaby) so that he would sleep.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The room&amp;rsquo;s door wasn&amp;rsquo;t fully closed. So, everytime I would pass by that door opening, he could see his mummy (Sonal).&#xA;He would get active again and hopeful that his mum would come to carry him. He would stretch his neck to see more of his mum.&#xA;This happened few times. So, I decided to close the door completely.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2500km</title>
      <link>http://pvsukalkar.in/misc/2500km/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2025 02:51:11 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pvsukalkar.in/misc/2500km/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Will we be able to do such a long travel ? What if Samu falls sick and we need to rush to hospital ? Where will we find hospital in a new city ?&#xA;What if Sonal falls sick ? How will we take care of Samu ? What if I fall sick ? How will we come back without driving from so far ?&#xA;What if some accident happens and whole family is injured ? What if car breaks down in journey ? What if we encounter some thief ? &amp;hellip; and what not.&#xA;All such negative thoughts were looming over head before the journey.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
