<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Diary Of An Observer</title>
    <link>http://pvsukalkar.in/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Diary Of An Observer</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 21:56:59 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://pvsukalkar.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Nginx</title>
      <link>http://pvsukalkar.in/tech/nginx/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 21:56:59 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pvsukalkar.in/tech/nginx/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nginx can be used for multiple purposes like web serving, load balancing or reverse proxying. It was designed to solve C10k problem so obviously it can handle large number of connections simultaneously. Besides, it also excels at serving static content. But how does it achieve this ?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nginx follows an asynchronous event-driven architecture. There is a master process that manages all worker processes. Typically there are as many workers as there are CPU cores. Each worker has an event loop running inside it. When an event comes on socket, OS notifies worker. Worker registers interest in the event and moves ahead. When data is received from client, a read event is triggered which is then processed by worker. Thus, the worker continues with its events without being blocked.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iron Beneath the Rust</title>
      <link>http://pvsukalkar.in/tech/iron-beneath-the-rust/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 20:14:06 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pvsukalkar.in/tech/iron-beneath-the-rust/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Having worked on Python for 6+ years, learning Rust took me back to C/C++ days in college. Compile the code before running it. With that it also brought back the nostalgic fear of pointers. Rust put all of the fears to rest.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are two types of memory: Stack and Heap. As the name suggests on stack memory things will be put one above other and popped in reverse order. Since you know where you are putting things and removing from, stack memory is extremely fast.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Helping Yourself</title>
      <link>http://pvsukalkar.in/finance/helping-yourself/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 23:55:14 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pvsukalkar.in/finance/helping-yourself/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Sep 2023, I bought my Dzire car from Spinny. Car cost was around Rs. 5L. I thought of making a down payment of Rs. 1L and taking a loan of Rs. 4L. With the EMI the car would have costed me Rs 5.5L&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I had savings of more than Rs 5L in FD. I thought instead of paying interest to bank, why not take loan from myself ? I broke the Rs 5L FD and started an RD of Rs 20k for 3 years.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rustic</title>
      <link>http://pvsukalkar.in/tech/rust-ic/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 23:11:43 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pvsukalkar.in/tech/rust-ic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been hearing a lot about &lt;code&gt;Rust&lt;/code&gt; lately. How it is fast and achieves near C/C++ performance. So, I was thinking of usecases where I can use it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have been using Python (at work) for many years now. Python is a good starting point to embody business ideas as it significantly reduces development time. Libraries are readily available for almost all use cases.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But when your product is built and is handling traffic at scale, you need to go deeper. Python can be a barrier too sometimes. We have migrated one of our high-traffic module from Python (Django) to Java (Spring Webflux) and have seen a 5x impovement in response times. That got me thinking about other options too and eventual interest in &lt;code&gt;Rust&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Memory Overload</title>
      <link>http://pvsukalkar.in/tech/memory-overload/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 21:02:55 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pvsukalkar.in/tech/memory-overload/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An Issue was reported that videos were not being uploaded from google drive to S3. We have an asynchronous task that transfers files from google drive to S3 (for further processing).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My first assumption was that the tasks might have been queued. Also there weren&amp;rsquo;t any sentry alerts, so I ignored the issue. Even after few hours, the issue was not resolved so it seemed something was cooking.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I tried to upload a 2MB file from drive and it got processed instantaneously. So, the pipeline was working fine. I looked at the file that they were trying to upload. It was a whopping 8.3GB file. That raised some doubts. Is google drive blocking such file ? Is some network connection getting reset ? Is S3 limiting file upload ?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Whats Cookie-ing</title>
      <link>http://pvsukalkar.in/tech/whats-cookie-ing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2025 22:46:43 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pvsukalkar.in/tech/whats-cookie-ing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are trying to improve security of our CDN with cloudfront cookies. Cloudfront provides two approaches: one using signed urls and the other using signed cookies. The later suits better for our media usecase where there are lot of fragmented files.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I generated a privately signed cookie and sent it in an API response. Then I used this in sending an API request from Postman. And voila it worked. POC was successful.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Itch</title>
      <link>http://pvsukalkar.in/finance/the-itch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2025 23:56:07 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pvsukalkar.in/finance/the-itch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-itch&#34;&gt;The Itch&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Few Years ago, I used to invest in Share Market. Every morning, I used to open the app around 9am and start tracking the movements. I used to save Rs 10-12k to invest in market for that month. Depending on how the market is moving, I would buy few shares. When I bought some share and at end of day I earned even few rupees profit, it would make me happy. It was an achievement. Throughout the day I would fidget around the trading app checking if there has been any positive movement.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hosting a Site</title>
      <link>http://pvsukalkar.in/tech/hosting-a-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 19:34:07 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pvsukalkar.in/tech/hosting-a-site/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;hosting-a-website&#34;&gt;Hosting A WebSite&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now that you have purchased a domain, what will it show ? where will your code reside ? where your images / video files be stored ? how will you run scripts to build your code ?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s go step by step.&#xA;Say I just want to display an &lt;code&gt;index.html&lt;/code&gt; page on my website to host my resume.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you have an AWS account, a simplest way is to create a static website in S3. Create a bucket in S3, create an &lt;code&gt;index.html&lt;/code&gt; page in it. Enable &lt;code&gt;static website hosting&lt;/code&gt; for your bucket. Create &lt;code&gt;CNAME&lt;/code&gt; record in your domain to point to this static website and your resume is up.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Buying a Domain</title>
      <link>http://pvsukalkar.in/tech/buying-a-domain/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 19:22:01 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pvsukalkar.in/tech/buying-a-domain/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;buying-a-domain&#34;&gt;Buying A Domain&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Say you want to build a house. Before that you will need to buy a plot (land) where you will build the house.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Similarly, if you want to build something that people can see on internet, you will have to buy some space on internet.&#xA;This space is &lt;code&gt;domain&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To purchase plot, you need to make registration at registrar office and pay stamp duty fees.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Similar is the process of buying a domain.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Turning A Liability Into An Asset</title>
      <link>http://pvsukalkar.in/finance/liability-to-asset/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 17:09:44 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pvsukalkar.in/finance/liability-to-asset/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;WFH days were over when we were called to office. I had got an extension of 6 months since we were expecting a child. In the meantime, I had to come to Bengaluru for office visits. During these visits, I checked about rents in Bengaluru. They had significantly shot up. Even a 1BHK would have been fine for me, but it did not come with car parking. So, I had to search for 2BHK. In a decent society it shot up to anywhere Rs 40k - Rs 50k.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://pvsukalkar.in/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 17:00:01 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pvsukalkar.in/about/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Free Website</title>
      <link>http://pvsukalkar.in/posts/free-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 16:09:56 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pvsukalkar.in/posts/free-website/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;hosting-free-website-with-github-and-hugo&#34;&gt;Hosting Free Website With Github And Hugo&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Create a github repository with your username as &lt;code&gt;psukalka.github.io&lt;/code&gt;. Github only allows one website per username (it can have multiple pages though). So, you need to user your username in the repository.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Clone the repository on local system&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Install hugo on your system&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mark this repository as a hugo website using: &lt;code&gt;hugo new site . --force&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Add some theme. Ex: &lt;code&gt;git submodule add https://github.com/theNewDynamic/gohugo-theme-ananke.git themes/ananke&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
