<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Diary Of An Observer</title>
    <link>http://pvsukalkar.in/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Diary Of An Observer</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Jul 2025 21:24:34 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://pvsukalkar.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Management With Sentry</title>
      <link>http://pvsukalkar.in/management/management-with-sentry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jul 2025 21:24:34 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pvsukalkar.in/management/management-with-sentry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m helping a friend in managing his tech venture. He got the project built with a Consultancy Service and they have done quite a good job. When I started on the project it was a live app working in production. I had to manage the tech team given that the consultants had now done their job.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Codebase was in Python (Django) which I am already familiar with from my office work. I started going through the codebase. I understood the flows in a few days. I started giving time after office hours while their team used to work in daytime. So, there was no syncing between me and the team. Neither did I have any test app build that I could use to identify important API flows. On top of that everything seemed to work, so I didn&amp;rsquo;t have any way to barge in. As a production project whatever I would imagine should be in place was already there and even better than I would think in some places. When something is working, it is difficult to make your way in.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VPN</title>
      <link>http://pvsukalkar.in/tech/vpn/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 18:04:41 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pvsukalkar.in/tech/vpn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We generally use VPN (Virtual Private Network) to test whether content piece is accessible from another country. Using VPN our servers are tricked as if the request is coming from another country. How does this happen ?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On a simple level, when VPN app is running on my device it will send all my requests (app or browser requests) to the VPN server that is located in some another country. VPN server will then forward these requests to the destination server. Since the request has actually come from another country, destination server will respond. This response will then be forwarded back to me. Thus VPN has acted as a middle-man or proxy to send my request.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Slack Integration</title>
      <link>http://pvsukalkar.in/tech/slack/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2025 11:11:53 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pvsukalkar.in/tech/slack/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With scale, time becomes of essence in resolving an issue. Thus, identifying and resolving issues quickly becomes of essence. Collating data from multiple sources to debug an issue is not desirable in such case. If your workspace is on Slack, then getting alerts on Slack increases visibility and saves time in crisis (when it matters). Slack can also be used to send alerts of any background tasks like celery tasks, jenkins deployments, &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gunicorn</title>
      <link>http://pvsukalkar.in/tech/gunicorn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 18:10:56 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pvsukalkar.in/tech/gunicorn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While development, we run Django application using &lt;code&gt;python manage.py runserver&lt;/code&gt;. But that is not recommended for production use. Why so ?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Firstly, in development mode, lot of details are returned which expose internals of system. This is a security risk in production. Secondly, application doesn&amp;rsquo;t auto-restart if it crashes with some error. Memory leaks in application accumulate over time eventually leading to crashing of server. Load can&amp;rsquo;t be balanced across CPU cores. Then static files are served synchronously this would result in queuing of requests. In dev mode server runs as a single thread so it can&amp;rsquo;t handle multiple concurrent requests thus increasing overall response time. There isn&amp;rsquo;t connection pooling for database connections. Overall it is not a reliable setup that should be used in production.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aspera</title>
      <link>http://pvsukalkar.in/tech/aspera/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2025 07:42:43 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pvsukalkar.in/tech/aspera/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I heard about &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ibm.com/products/aspera&#34;&gt;Aspera&lt;/a&gt; first time today. It is not a file storage, rather a file transfer technology by IBM. But what is the benefit ? and why do you need another technology ? Let&amp;rsquo;s dig deeper.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Say, you are a production house. You produce movies or videos. The raw content is generally quite large in size. Like 100s of GB and sometimes can even go in TBs. Transferring this much content via network is quite slow. Instead just sending the content via hard disk is faster. Aspera shines for such cases. Despite size of content you get consistent speed. This is what happens internally.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apache Bench</title>
      <link>http://pvsukalkar.in/tech/apache-bench/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 20:57:38 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pvsukalkar.in/tech/apache-bench/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I wanted to replace &lt;code&gt;python manage.py runserver&lt;/code&gt; command with &lt;code&gt;uwsgi&lt;/code&gt; for production. But before taking any decision I want it to be assessed with some data. Even if some blog says uwsgi can handle better concurrent load, memory management and caching why should I believe it ? How can I test to be clear.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For starter, I can write a python script that can send n number of requests and I can make them concurrent calls using async / threads. But is there any other readily available option ? When I explored, there is an option: &lt;code&gt;Apache Bench (ab)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Jenkins</title>
      <link>http://pvsukalkar.in/tech/jenkins/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2025 23:01:50 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pvsukalkar.in/tech/jenkins/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have used Jenkins to deploy jobs but that&amp;rsquo;s the extent of my usage. I was going to deep-dive into Jenkins. But before that I got a thought, why not think of building Jenkins if I had to build one ? If I was to build Jenkins, how would I have done it ?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So, Jenkins for me is an &lt;code&gt;automated deployment&lt;/code&gt; tool. So, before automating something, how would I have done the deployment manually ? Say, I want to deploy a Django project from GitHub to production. I would follow these steps:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sentry - For The Black</title>
      <link>http://pvsukalkar.in/tech/sentry/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 10:26:08 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pvsukalkar.in/tech/sentry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Where can I find the logs ?&lt;/em&gt; was one of the initial questions that I asked while understanding our system. I came from a background where you need to see logs to find issues. I was taken aback when I heard that they don&amp;rsquo;t capture logs. I kept wondering how they resolve issues in production.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been 5+ years now working in the system and I have rarely used logs. It brings a smile to my face when some new joinee asks for logs. With Sentry catching errors has become quite easy. Enable sentry on one of the servers and if any case throws error alerts are raised immediately. Whoever sent the buggy code is responsible to fix it immediately. Sentry alert gives you all details you would ever need to fix that bug. Which API ? Which Machine ? Which line ? What error ? What were the local variables ? &amp;hellip; Thus, we have been able to scale to millions of users without ever depending on logs. Any bug that creeps in, gets killed in nascent stage.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maintaining A Database</title>
      <link>http://pvsukalkar.in/tech/maintaining-database/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 23:53:13 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pvsukalkar.in/tech/maintaining-database/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We use Django Framework in our system. Django comes with its own ORM for relational databases. There are few tables which are being used from 7+ years now, so we decided to look into them.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To check how much space a table is using, we can run following Postgres query:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;     SELECT&#xA;        schemaname,&#xA;        tablename,&#xA;        pg_size_pretty(pg_total_relation_size(schemaname||&amp;#39;.&amp;#39;||tablename)) as total_size,&#xA;        pg_size_pretty(pg_relation_size(schemaname||&amp;#39;.&amp;#39;||tablename)) as table_size,&#xA;        pg_size_pretty(pg_indexes_size(schemaname||&amp;#39;.&amp;#39;||tablename)) as indexes_size&#xA;    FROM pg_tables&#xA;    WHERE tablename = &amp;#39;{table_name}&amp;#39;;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;It turned out that the table is using 1.5GB space and its indexes are using 6.5GB space. This came as a surprise to me as I was always under the impression that indexes are smaller than table. Yes, indeed they are smaller but how many indexes you create also matters. It turns out that we had 50+ indexes on our table. Obviously not all of them are being used. So, I checked indexes and their usage with this query:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Conundrum: Sync Or Async</title>
      <link>http://pvsukalkar.in/tech/the-conundrum/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 21:43:16 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pvsukalkar.in/tech/the-conundrum/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Suppose I migrate my code from being synchronous to asynchronous what does change ? Let&amp;rsquo;s try to think through.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Synchronous code execution is very predictable and linear. If you make some network call, it will relax there till the data comes. On the contrary, asynchronous code is quite busy. The poor guy keeps on running in (event) loop juggling multiple tasks concurrently. If it makes any network call it will register an event for that and pause execution there. Meanwhile it (eventloop) will pick and process some other event which is ready.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Video</title>
      <link>http://pvsukalkar.in/tech/understanding-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 May 2025 00:56:39 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pvsukalkar.in/tech/understanding-video/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Say, I have a &lt;code&gt;video.mp4&lt;/code&gt; file on my system. What exactly does it contain ? The outermost layer is called &lt;code&gt;Container&lt;/code&gt;. There are various type of containers &lt;code&gt;mp4&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;mkv&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;mov&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;flv&lt;/code&gt;, &amp;hellip; Container contains metadata about the file like its title, duration, creation date, &amp;hellip; Then it contains streams of data. They can be video streams, audio streams, subtitle streams, &amp;hellip; This is pictorially explained in following image:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://pvsukalkar.in/images/video-container.svg&#34; alt=&#34;Video Container&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Swiss Army Knife</title>
      <link>http://pvsukalkar.in/tech/the-swiss-knife/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 22:38:25 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pvsukalkar.in/tech/the-swiss-knife/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;FFmpeg is called the Swiss Army Knife for video and audio. Whatever you want to do with media like compressing, scaling, editing, encoding, decoding, transcoding, streaming, &amp;hellip; FFmpeg can do everything. If it&amp;rsquo;s so special, let&amp;rsquo;s start using it. You can install &lt;a href=&#34;https://ffmpeg.bufferhead.com/&#34;&gt;FFmpeg&lt;/a&gt; on your system.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s download some video &lt;code&gt;video_1.mp4&lt;/code&gt; . I want to get details about this video. I can do so using:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;ffprobe -v quiet -print_format json -show_format -show_streams video_1.mp4&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here we used &lt;code&gt;ffprobe&lt;/code&gt; (that usually comes with ffmpeg).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DRM</title>
      <link>http://pvsukalkar.in/tech/drm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 00:59:07 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pvsukalkar.in/tech/drm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Billions Of Dollars are annually lost by production companies due to piracy.&#xA;Someone can download your content and distribute it on free channel. Thus, you lose on revenue that user might have paid.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;How do you solve this problem ? Or can we even solve it ?&#xA;If someone is playing a movie on TV and then recording it again through high quality camera (thus recreating it), you can&amp;rsquo;t block this. This is called Analog Hole. Thus, you can&amp;rsquo;t protect 100% piracy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vector Graphics</title>
      <link>http://pvsukalkar.in/tech/vector-graphics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 19:51:31 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pvsukalkar.in/tech/vector-graphics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you zoom in on any image on your phone, it starts breaking after 2x - 3x zoom. You can see square pixel blocks. But what happens when you zoom in on google map ? Despite how much you zoom (till you hit last block) it doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to break. I observed similar thing with Figma.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What is the magic here ? Why doesn&amp;rsquo;t it break ? Let&amp;rsquo;s try to reverse engineer the problem. How would I achieve it if I want to create such google map like functionality.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Video Scrubbing</title>
      <link>http://pvsukalkar.in/tech/video-scrubbing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 20:32:53 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pvsukalkar.in/tech/video-scrubbing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While watching YouTube video, if you hover over the seek bar you can preview video image of that location.&#xA;You can see images even at 10 min even though only 30 sec of video has buffered yet.&#xA;So, if the video has not loaded till 10 min, how is the video player able to display image at that location ? Isn&amp;rsquo;t it interesting ?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This happens with a feature called video scrubbing. We need to process the uploaded video for video scrubbing.&#xA;When a video is uploaded (say of 10 min), we can take snapshots at regular intervals (of say 3sec).&#xA;So, for a 10 min video there will be 10*60/3 = 200 snapshots. We can generate these snapshots using ffmpeg.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HAProxy</title>
      <link>http://pvsukalkar.in/tech/haproxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 23:15:11 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pvsukalkar.in/tech/haproxy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When you go to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.haproxy.org/&#34;&gt;HAProxy Site&lt;/a&gt;, the small case fonts and hardly any effort on UI make you think &lt;code&gt;do they even maintain this site ?&lt;/code&gt; Are HAProxy days done ? But if you make effort to read along, you fumble on this line: &lt;em&gt;Most users report having never ever faced any single crash and claim that HAProxy is the most solid part of their infrastructure. Finding machines with HAProxy processes being up for more than 3 years is not exceptional at all!&lt;/em&gt; Phew!! Flexing of highest caliber.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Caddy</title>
      <link>http://pvsukalkar.in/tech/caddy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 01:10:18 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pvsukalkar.in/tech/caddy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just as a golf caddie makes the game easier for golfers by carrying their equipments and offering guidance, the Caddy web server aims to make web hosting easier by handling complicated tasks (like SSL/TLS certificates) automatically. With caddy, you don&amp;rsquo;t need to worry about your certificate expiration. It started back in the days when Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt was just starting and enabling HTTPS on your website was a headache and costly.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nginx</title>
      <link>http://pvsukalkar.in/tech/nginx/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 21:56:59 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pvsukalkar.in/tech/nginx/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nginx can be used for multiple purposes like web serving, load balancing or reverse proxying. It was designed to solve C10k problem so obviously it can handle large number of connections simultaneously. Besides, it also excels at serving static content. But how does it achieve this ?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nginx follows an asynchronous event-driven architecture. There is a master process that manages all worker processes. Typically there are as many workers as there are CPU cores. Each worker has an event loop running inside it. When an event comes on socket, OS notifies worker. Worker registers interest in the event and moves ahead. When data is received from client, a read event is triggered which is then processed by worker. Thus, the worker continues with its events without being blocked.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iron Beneath the Rust</title>
      <link>http://pvsukalkar.in/tech/iron-beneath-the-rust/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 20:14:06 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pvsukalkar.in/tech/iron-beneath-the-rust/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Having worked on Python for 6+ years, learning Rust took me back to C/C++ days in college. Compile the code before running it. With that it also brought back the nostalgic fear of pointers. Rust put all of the fears to rest.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are two types of memory: Stack and Heap. As the name suggests on stack memory things will be put one above other and popped in reverse order. Since you know where you are putting things and removing from, stack memory is extremely fast.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Helping Yourself</title>
      <link>http://pvsukalkar.in/finance/helping-yourself/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 23:55:14 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pvsukalkar.in/finance/helping-yourself/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Sep 2023, I bought my Dzire car from Spinny. Car cost was around Rs. 5L. I thought of making a down payment of Rs. 1L and taking a loan of Rs. 4L. With the EMI the car would have costed me Rs 5.5L&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I had savings of more than Rs 5L in FD. I thought instead of paying interest to bank, why not take loan from myself ? I broke the Rs 5L FD and started an RD of Rs 20k for 3 years.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rustic</title>
      <link>http://pvsukalkar.in/tech/rust-ic/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 23:11:43 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pvsukalkar.in/tech/rust-ic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been hearing a lot about &lt;code&gt;Rust&lt;/code&gt; lately. How it is fast and achieves near C/C++ performance. So, I was thinking of usecases where I can use it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have been using Python (at work) for many years now. Python is a good starting point to embody business ideas as it significantly reduces development time. Libraries are readily available for almost all use cases.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But when your product is built and is handling traffic at scale, you need to go deeper. Python can be a barrier too sometimes. We have migrated one of our high-traffic module from Python (Django) to Java (Spring Webflux) and have seen a 5x impovement in response times. That got me thinking about other options too and eventual interest in &lt;code&gt;Rust&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Memory Overload</title>
      <link>http://pvsukalkar.in/tech/memory-overload/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 21:02:55 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pvsukalkar.in/tech/memory-overload/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An Issue was reported that videos were not being uploaded from google drive to S3. We have an asynchronous task that transfers files from google drive to S3 (for further processing).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My first assumption was that the tasks might have been queued. Also there weren&amp;rsquo;t any sentry alerts, so I ignored the issue. Even after few hours, the issue was not resolved so it seemed something was cooking.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I tried to upload a 2MB file from drive and it got processed instantaneously. So, the pipeline was working fine. I looked at the file that they were trying to upload. It was a whopping 8.3GB file. That raised some doubts. Is google drive blocking such file ? Is some network connection getting reset ? Is S3 limiting file upload ?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Whats Cookie-ing</title>
      <link>http://pvsukalkar.in/tech/whats-cookie-ing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2025 22:46:43 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pvsukalkar.in/tech/whats-cookie-ing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are trying to improve security of our CDN with cloudfront cookies. Cloudfront provides two approaches: one using signed urls and the other using signed cookies. The later suits better for our media usecase where there are lot of fragmented files.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I generated a privately signed cookie and sent it in an API response. Then I used this in sending an API request from Postman. And voila it worked. POC was successful.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Itch</title>
      <link>http://pvsukalkar.in/finance/the-itch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2025 23:56:07 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pvsukalkar.in/finance/the-itch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Few Years ago, I used to invest in Share Market. Every morning, I used to open the app around 9am and start tracking the movements. I used to save Rs 10-12k to invest in market for that month. Depending on how the market is moving, I would buy few shares. When I bought some share and at end of day I earned even few rupees profit, it would make me happy. It was an achievement. Throughout the day I would fidget around the trading app checking if there has been any positive movement.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hosting a Website</title>
      <link>http://pvsukalkar.in/tech/hosting-a-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 19:34:07 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pvsukalkar.in/tech/hosting-a-site/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Now that you have purchased a domain, what will it show ? where will your code reside ? where your images / video files be stored ? how will you run scripts to build your code ?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s go step by step.&#xA;Say I just want to display an &lt;code&gt;index.html&lt;/code&gt; page on my website to host my resume.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you have an AWS account, a simplest way is to create a static website in S3. Create a bucket in S3, create an &lt;code&gt;index.html&lt;/code&gt; page in it. Enable &lt;code&gt;static website hosting&lt;/code&gt; for your bucket. Create &lt;code&gt;CNAME&lt;/code&gt; record in your domain to point to this static website and your resume is up.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Buying a Domain</title>
      <link>http://pvsukalkar.in/tech/buying-a-domain/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 19:22:01 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pvsukalkar.in/tech/buying-a-domain/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Say you want to build a house. Before that you will need to buy a plot (land) where you will build the house.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Similarly, if you want to build something that people can see on internet, you will have to buy some space on internet.&#xA;This space is &lt;code&gt;domain&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To purchase plot, you need to make registration at registrar office and pay stamp duty fees.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Similar is the process of buying a domain.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Turning A Liability Into An Asset</title>
      <link>http://pvsukalkar.in/finance/liability-to-asset/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 17:09:44 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pvsukalkar.in/finance/liability-to-asset/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;WFH days were over when we were called to office. I had got an extension of 6 months since we were expecting a child. In the meantime, I had to come to Bengaluru for office visits. During these visits, I checked about rents in Bengaluru. They had significantly shot up. Even a 1BHK would have been fine for me, but it did not come with car parking. So, I had to search for 2BHK. In a decent society it shot up to anywhere Rs 40k - Rs 50k.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://pvsukalkar.in/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 17:00:01 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pvsukalkar.in/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You are breathing, of course, but unconsciously. Just close your eyes and observe the air coming through your nose. Suddenly your breathing pattern changes. What was just an unnoticeable in-out action suddenly becomes noticeable. You start filling more air in your chest. You breathe out lesser. If you continue for few minutes, your spine starts getting erect. Randomness in thoughts reduces&amp;hellip; All with simply observing your breathing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you then start using your mind to question the observations you dig even deeper.  Why am I breathing ? Ok, but why am I breathing so many times in a second ? Don&amp;rsquo;t know. Just stop breathing. In a minute, you will feel uncontrollable and you will start gasping for air. So, one thing is established. Whatever it is that breathing is doing is very important. But what is it that I need every second ? Say, I&amp;rsquo;m sleeping still I&amp;rsquo;m breathing. When I&amp;rsquo;m running still I&amp;rsquo;m running. What is it that I&amp;rsquo;m needing every second ? I need energy every second. Though I may not be doing any external activity lot of activity is happening and everything needs energy. So, there has to be some correlation of breathing with energy. If I&amp;rsquo;m breathing where is it being stored ? I can observe my chest and belly bulging while breathing in. So, that indicates presence of some hollow space inside my body to hold the air. Is the air that I&amp;rsquo;m inhaling same as the air that I&amp;rsquo;m exhaling ? Well, if it is same then body did not use it at all. And if it did not use it then what was need of breathing. So, the exhaling air must be different from the inhaling air&amp;hellip; And you can go on deeper.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Free Website</title>
      <link>http://pvsukalkar.in/posts/free-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 16:09:56 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pvsukalkar.in/posts/free-website/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;hosting-free-website-with-github-and-hugo&#34;&gt;Hosting Free Website With Github And Hugo&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Create a github repository with your username as &lt;code&gt;psukalka.github.io&lt;/code&gt;. Github only allows one website per username (it can have multiple pages though). So, you need to user your username in the repository.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Clone the repository on local system&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Install hugo on your system&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mark this repository as a hugo website using: &lt;code&gt;hugo new site . --force&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Add some theme. Ex: &lt;code&gt;git submodule add https://github.com/theNewDynamic/gohugo-theme-ananke.git themes/ananke&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
