<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tech on An Observer</title>
    <link>http://pvsukalkar.in/tech/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tech on An Observer</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2025 22:46:43 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://pvsukalkar.in/tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Whats Cookie-ing</title>
      <link>http://pvsukalkar.in/tech/whats-cookie-ing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2025 22:46:43 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pvsukalkar.in/tech/whats-cookie-ing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are trying to improve security of our CDN with cloudfront cookies. Cloudfront provides two approaches: one using signed urls and the other using signed cookies. The later suits better for our media usecase where there are lot of fragmented files.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I generated a privately signed cookie and sent it in an API response. Then I used this in sending an API request from Postman. And voila it worked. POC was successful.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hosting a Site</title>
      <link>http://pvsukalkar.in/tech/hosting-a-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 19:34:07 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pvsukalkar.in/tech/hosting-a-site/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;hosting-a-website&#34;&gt;Hosting A WebSite&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now that you have purchased a domain, what will it show ? where will your code reside ? where your images / video files be stored ? how will you run scripts to build your code ?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s go step by step.&#xA;Say I just want to display an &lt;code&gt;index.html&lt;/code&gt; page on my website to host my resume.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you have an AWS account, a simplest way is to create a static website in S3. Create a bucket in S3, create an &lt;code&gt;index.html&lt;/code&gt; page in it. Enable &lt;code&gt;static website hosting&lt;/code&gt; for your bucket. Create &lt;code&gt;CNAME&lt;/code&gt; record in your domain to point to this static website and your resume is up.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Buying a Domain</title>
      <link>http://pvsukalkar.in/tech/buying-a-domain/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 19:22:01 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pvsukalkar.in/tech/buying-a-domain/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;buying-a-domain&#34;&gt;Buying A Domain&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Say you want to build a house. Before that you will need to buy a plot (land) where you will build the house.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Similarly, if you want to build something that people can see on internet, you will have to buy some space on internet.&#xA;This space is &lt;code&gt;domain&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To purchase plot, you need to make registration at registrar office and pay stamp duty fees.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Similar is the process of buying a domain.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
