<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Finance on Diary Of An Observer</title>
    <link>http://pvsukalkar.in/finance/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Finance on Diary Of An Observer</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 23:55:14 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://pvsukalkar.in/finance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Helping Yourself</title>
      <link>http://pvsukalkar.in/finance/helping-yourself/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 23:55:14 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pvsukalkar.in/finance/helping-yourself/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Sep 2023, I bought my Dzire car from Spinny. Car cost was around Rs. 5L. I thought of making a down payment of Rs. 1L and taking a loan of Rs. 4L. With the EMI the car would have costed me Rs 5.5L&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I had savings of more than Rs 5L in FD. I thought instead of paying interest to bank, why not take loan from myself ? I broke the Rs 5L FD and started an RD of Rs 20k for 3 years.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Itch</title>
      <link>http://pvsukalkar.in/finance/the-itch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2025 23:56:07 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pvsukalkar.in/finance/the-itch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Few Years ago, I used to invest in Share Market. Every morning, I used to open the app around 9am and start tracking the movements. I used to save Rs 10-12k to invest in market for that month. Depending on how the market is moving, I would buy few shares. When I bought some share and at end of day I earned even few rupees profit, it would make me happy. It was an achievement. Throughout the day I would fidget around the trading app checking if there has been any positive movement.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Turning A Liability Into An Asset</title>
      <link>http://pvsukalkar.in/finance/liability-to-asset/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 17:09:44 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pvsukalkar.in/finance/liability-to-asset/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;WFH days were over when we were called to office. I had got an extension of 6 months since we were expecting a child. In the meantime, I had to come to Bengaluru for office visits. During these visits, I checked about rents in Bengaluru. They had significantly shot up. Even a 1BHK would have been fine for me, but it did not come with car parking. So, I had to search for 2BHK. In a decent society it shot up to anywhere Rs 40k - Rs 50k.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
